Guide to the James Reed Papers, 1907-1941 JL012
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
James Reed Papers,
1907-1941
JL012
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
0.5 Linear feet
Reed, James
Scope and Content
The collection consists of reports and correspondence concerning the construction of the Golden Gate Bridge and some material dealing with Reed's earlier activities, such as his association with the Celite Company in Los Angeles, Public Works and management activities in Philadelphia, and involvement in a project on the Isthmus of Tehuantepec. The collection covers the years 1907-1941.
Biographical Note
James Reed was a graduate of the United States Naval Academy and of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. As an officer of the Naval Construction Corps, he served at the Philadelphia, Puget Sound, and Mare Island Navy Yards, specializing in management and labor problems. For two years, while on special leave of absence, he acted as Assistant Director of Public Works for the city of Philadelphia. He resigned from the Navy in 1920 and managed various California corporations until his appointment as general manager of the Golden Gate Bridge and Highway District in 1933. James Reed was a consulting professor at Stanford University, in the Graduate School of Business.
Provenance
Gift of Mrs. James Reed to the Jackson Library of Business, 1943. Transferred to the Department of Special Collections in 1979.
Access Restrictions
None.
- Correspondence re: Reed's position as Assistant Director of Public Works for Philadelphia, (July 1913-Nov 1916) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Isthmus of Tehuantepac, (Jan 1907, April 1912, and April 1924-Oct 1925) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Maps
  - Correspondence
  - Reports
- Celite Company, Los Angeles, (Dec 1926-Dec 1928) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Reports
  - Correspondence (Reed-Production Manager)
  - Charts
- Golden Gate Bridge and Highway District, (1932-1941) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: James Reed, in and out
- Golden Gate Bridge, (1930-1937) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Description of the principal features and insurable risks of the Golden Gate Bridge; George E. Billings Co., insurance advisors.
- Golden Gate Bridge: (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - a) Investigation of criticism of foundation by Dr. Bailey Willis; report of building committee, (November 1934)
  - b) Rapid transit over Golden Gate Bridge; report of Joseph B. Strauss, (Dec 1934)
  - c) Sausalito Lateral report, (July 1937)
- Golden Gate Bridge, (April 1934-April 1936) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Reed's reports to Board of Directors of the Golden Gate Bridge and Highway District
- Golden Gate Bridge Reports to Board of Directors, (May 1936-August 1937) (Box 1, Folder 8)